# JOHN McMullan

Canton, Georgia

Phone: (770) 853-5515 | Email: john.mcmullan0819@gmail.com LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/john-e-mcmullan | GitHub: Write out Link | Portfolio: Write out Link

#### **Summary**

Data Analyst with well developed leadership and communication skills and a work drive to be at the top of the field. A strong independent worker with experience in leading teams to gather data and present it in a digestible easy to understand manner.

#### **Technical Skills**

Tools: Excel VBA, Python, Matplotlib, Pandas, Jupyter Notebook, API

Databases: AWS

## **Projects**

Inflation for the everyday American | https://github.com/labywyntir/testbranching

- In this project we looked at the effects of inflation on things that effect the average Americans life like grocery prices, gas prices, purchasing habits, and wages.
- I took responsibility for answering how the Consumer Price Index affects minimum wage and common grocery prices and pulling data from the Bureau Labor of Statistics API.
- Tools / languages used: Python, Matplotlib, Pandas, Jupyter notebook, and the BLS API

## **Experience**

Elementary Music Teacher 2020-2021

Dug Gap Elementary Dalton, Georgia

Responsible for developing relationships with entire student body and their family, communication with parents, and building different programs for the benefit of the school. Key Accomplishments:

- Highest recruitment rate in program history at 60% of possible candidates
- Brought community back in a post covid-19 era

Band Director 2018-2020

#### New Hampstead High School Bloomingdale, Georgia

Responsible for recruitment and retention of upcoming students, running fundraising and other funding opportunities, developing relationships with entire student body and their family, and creating easy communication avenues for parents to reach me through.

Key Accomplishments:

- Increased retention rates by 10% for three straight years
- Increased funding by 300% in a title one area
- Maintained positive relationships with competitive directors

Beginning Band Director 2015-2018

Pooler Elementary School Pooler, Georgia

West Chatham Elementary School Pooler, Georgia

Responsible creating a brand new experimental curriculum, building recruitment numbers of students, and convincing parents to rent instruments.

Key Accomplishments:

- 85% retention rate year to year
- Fundraised enough money to start multiple beneficial programs

## **Education**

Boot Camp Certificate: Georgia Tech, Atlanta, GA

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Excel, VBA, Python, R, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Big Data, and Machine Learning.

**Bachelor in Music Education:** Georgia College and State University, Milledgeville, GA A 4 year program focused on learning how to build music programs, gaining musical skills and knowledge, and learning how to communicate that knowledge to students and parents.